[Music]
thanks for uh tuning in the Grateful
Dead a
uh a golden nugget if you will to uh to
our days and our
times
um and
uh
look
um this program
aims to help
you be informed basic simple that's it
okay my tagline is be awesome ian.com
that's i a n t r TTI i r I come to you
every
Wednesday from the Windwood District of
Miami
Florida it all started folks from the
zika scare that hit South Florida last
year and the outrage that was sparked
over the pesticide that was being
sprayed for it
Ned okay it just so happens that Ned was
engineered in the 1950s by the Chevron
Chemical
Corporation what is nailed it's also
known as
diam it's currently manufactured by Van
card Chemical Corporation out of Los
Angeles right if you have interest on my
opinion on
that just type in in Honey Colony just
as it sounds and that article will shoot
up Mariam hennon she runs honey Colony
she's been past guest on my
show we got lots and lots and lots of
stuff going on folks and if you tuned in
last
hour John kyaku joined us I mean this
guy is
amazing pardon me as I needs to sneeze
for a moment one
second I produce and I host and we're an
independent radio show and
um anyway so John is an American Legend
he's an American Legend
folks he stands up he stood up and he
will continue to stand up for your
rights your Liberties your freedoms and
your
Justice and he will do so if it costs
him two years in federal prison as it
did and as he basically described to
us you going to call me a
rat I'm going to call you
out you're a
liar and that's basically what he said
to the US government because
those above him I.E George
Bush were
apparently of the
knowledge that the Central Intelligence
Agency
was
torturing it may not seem like a big
deal to
you but put yourself in that person's
shoes put yourself in the person's shoes
of being torture getting slammed up
against the wall being waterboarded
whatever it
is it's not
right it's
wrong and as he
described the
tactics used by the
CIA the non- torturous build a report be
friendly to your
enemy was far more productive it was
just that it was
productive in getting
information to save other people's
lives the CIA that was the FBI the CIA
took a totally
different approach and it proved to be
disastrous and John stood up for it and
he said no you can't do this it's wrong
we've got a treaty with the
we we human beings are human
beings so like I said probably about
that 501 502 Mark John kiraku is a
legend folks and not just a legend
physically and emotionally and mentally
he is a legend for anybody to
map or duplicate their own
moral ethical
values if something is
wrong stand up for
it wow okay so that was the 4:00
hour in a few
moments we'll be joined by JP
lindroth and JP obtained his doctor
philosophy that's a
PhD and social and cultural anthropology
from the University of
Oxford and actually brought up Oxford in
my discussion with John Kaku
because Oxford just so happens to base
many of their
philosophical approaches
to what was handed down from the Greeks
and John happens to be Greek and
ancestry so JP will join us and talk to
us about out his new
book uh which uh is on
poetry let me first get in
to Julie's piece now there's a lot
happening on this program there's a lots
of
changes and I want to mention that there
are
now I think actually Four uh contri
ruting members to this program the first
is Julie
Gomez she's local to Miami and
she
um she's a journalism student at local
school here miam dat college and she
will be contributing a piece each
week we
also
welcome uh to the program
Melissa
Lopez and Melissa is based in Southern
California she's in Hollywood she has
radio experience and media
experience she will be contributing a
weekly piece for us and I just had an
incredible discussion this
afternoon
with a doctor based in New York that
takes a natural approach to remedy
something that's highly important
because as in the past we've talked
extensively about vaccines and that will
be a major point of discussion come
January
vaccines Dr Serena will be joining us in
the New
Year
finally our fourth
contributor who's jumping aboard is
Joshua
demerest he will be be editing he's got
a degree from winthrip University he
currently works for book
Logics based in Atlanta
Georgia he's got an
extensive
young
resume
of media and journalism and being a
contributor editor in fact he's
editor-in-chief of the magazine Gallows
Hill so those are all new developments
in the
program and um we just continue
to uh
grow
now the piece that Julie's delivered us
today has to do with a major topic from
last week and it en cringes on again
here we're talking about our rights our
liberties post
911 as we spoke about with
John we have lost major major major
rights and making the internet
neutralized in some form is a big issue
just like the Federal
Reserve the Federal Reserve the
economics that fund the US government
are centralized that's what the Federal
Reserve is a central bank from
everything that I know not an economist
I'm not a banker I'm not a
politician at the moment but that's what
the Federal Reserve is okay so when you
neutralize things it ENC cringes
on freedom and growth and Justice and
Liberty Julie delivers the following to
us under President Obama the FCC voted
in favor of net neutrality in order to
keep the internet open and free on
Thursday December 14th 2017 the FCC led
by anit pay ended net neutrality what is
net
neutrality now some of the terms that I
previously mentioned seem to conflict so
I apologize if I was using incorrect
terms but let's continue according to
Mariam Webster it's the idea principle
or requirement that internet service
providers should or must treat all
internet data as the same regardless of
its kind Source or destination to put it
simply Julia writes internet providers
can't charge websites like Netflix more
than websites like Facebook or Yahoo
despite their differences in how much
data or bandwidth they use or the deals
made between websites and internet
providers net neutrality also allowed a
small mom and pop Business website or
teenagers blog to be seen just as easily
as a Fortune 500
companies okay now that's important
because that's kind of what we're doing
here at Winwood radio at least on this
program discussions any minute of the
day one can open their internet browser
and find out what's going on in the
world hear or read the same story with
different perspectives even read stories
that broadcasting companies like Fox CNN
won't run but Vice or BBC News will
however since internet providers are now
allowed to choose which websites have an
easier time connecting to our phones the
numerous choices we have gain
information will soon begin to decline
stars like Jimmy Kimmel and John Oliver
along with 83% of the American
population strongly opposed the
repealing net neutrality despite the
strong opinions of many regarding it the
FCC will vote three or two 3 to2 on
repeal repealing it this not only
affects stream websites it also affects
artists whom use Instagram Twitter
Facebook Etsy and similar sites that
utilize the open internet and various
opportunities it offers to make a living
artists like Alex Cohen the creator of
tiny sneak comics and comedians like
Mario ril depend on social media to
display their
Creations the Internet isn't what it is
because of isps but as a result of
millions of artists and creators who
rely on people having unburdened access
to what they're making take that away
and it's going to look a lot more like
cable the dreaded television segmented
beyond recognition and impossible for
individuals to be successful on their
own and it's not that television is not
a great invention it is actually
invented in San Francisco but it's the
content that is allowed to infiltrate
the hours of consumption on the
television Julia continues I think any
creator with an online following
regardless of their medium has a
responsibility to speak up in support of
net neutrality because it's not it's
excuse me it's truly not a political or
partisan issue it's about the future of
the internet as we know it Cohen wrote
me when asked for a statement again this
is Julie
speaking though the vast majority of
these dependent those dependent on the
internet have begun to fear the worst
ramill stated this quote big companies
are always trying to over their
consumers one way or another all they
care about is money artists especially
have always dealt with situations like
this in one form or another one thing is
certain whether it's online or stage or
in the street we will always express
ourselves end quote exclamation end
quote citizens are choosing to express
themselves by calling their State
Attorneys General offic insist they join
the multi-state lawsuit against the FCC
starting by New York's Attorney General
Eric Schneiderman Schneiderman I think
it is Florida State Attorney General Pam
Bondi and Pam is not announced any plans
to join the multi suit lawsuit however
her office number for citizenship
Services is 850- 414 3990 thank you
Julie she continues when net neutrality
is typed into search engine many
articles titled net neutrality rules are
dead will my bill go up from USA Today
or net neutrality vote what this means
for consumers from many post pop
people are scared their way of life is
going to dramatically
change many are limited to around two or
three internet providers if they're
lucky once companies start raising their
prices those who can't afford it might
have regress back to a time without
internet at their
homes the number of social media users
May soon begin to dwindle if providers
begin to outrageously increase their
prices amen
P can still tweet photos of his giant
Reese's Pieces peanut butter mug but
it'll be vain in Americans no longer
afford to log into their Twitter
accounts despite the cons this has for
consumers American citizens might agree
the most troubling part of it all is the
question no one has answered yet if 83%
of American population vo their
disapproval why did the FCC still repeal
net
neutrality
folks everything leads
back to
money and in then money in the United
States it's called the Federal
Reserve Julia continues and those are my
comments by the way citizens actively
signed petitions called the leaders of
their States government as well directly
calling the FCC despite the opposition
met against the repealing of net
neutrality pay Brendan Carr and Michael
O'Reilly all voted for it they ignored
the voice of the people and chose option
like companies such as AT&T and
Comcast shout outs says
Julie
patreon.com tiny snck Comics that's p a
t r o
n.com t i n s n k Comics shout out
facebook.com SL tiny snack
Comics shout out facebook.com Mari
ramill comedy that's m a r i o r a m i l
c o m e d
y and again Julie is asking for
all to write to Pam
bonding floral.com
cont and her number again
is 850- 414
0 if you have luck and you can get
through on that number let me know.com
that's i a n t TTI r.com radio if you
choose and I'll be back folks with JP
lindra thanks for tuning in to your 5:00
hour
of discussions I'm your host T TR this
is wi
[Music]
radio
my
[Music]
oh
the time is 528 that's pm. Eastern
Standard
again this is Winwood radio.com I'm your
weekly host for the show discussions
based out of the Winwood District of
Miami Florida and this afternoon we have
on program for the second time uh very
fortunate to have JP lindru rejoining us
JP are you
there yes thank you and thank you for
the invitation again it's my my honor
how did it go last time um we had a we
had a really cool discussion it just so
happened that the last time you came on
the program it was national news um what
was going on in Spain and so it was it
was an interesting dynamic because um
for a few few weeks prior to that I'd
had this marvelous Talent uh Pascal Val
um and she happened to uh be on the show
that day and so we we took an
interesting approach to merging the two
conversations but uh um what's going on
in your life since then how are
things everything's great and thanks a
lot yeah and um you know I'm on my way
to Brazil uh next week and just want to
give a quick shout out to uh my
Brazilian girlfriend her name is Casia
which is the basis of part of the book
of poetry that we're gonna talk about I
guess cool and it's her birthday today
and the reason why I wanted to shout out
just it's her birthday today so I just
wanted to wish her happy birthday at
police annivers audio wow
sorry
I very cool dude um you you speak a
little Portuguese I guess or is that the
extent of it yes I I'm fluent in
Portuguese and Spanish and uh so
yeah all right um and and and where does
is it
Kasha Casia yes Casia where where does
she live
she lives in sou Pao Brazil in sou Paulo
okay I haven't been have you I'm sure
you've been so so you know that I did uh
my fbite research in Brazil in manous
okay which is in the Amazon and uh and
so um my next well my next uh
non-fiction book my anthropological book
which I'm it's the proposal is getting
reviewed now um is based on that
research when I um you know interviewed
and researched eight different ethnic
groups within the the city of manow
which is in the the biggest city in the
Brazilian
Amazon okay and and most of John is it
is it is it correct to say that
the how do you summarize what you do now
you you're a you're obviously a doctor
of philosophy uh you teach classes at a
couple different institutions I think um
what's your main focus what what is JP
Linder what how are you changing the
world okay so okay um well right now I
mean I'm teaching uh the honors program
at Title One School uh the Royal Palm
Beach High School I'm teaching in their
their ath program which is Cambridge
University based program uh US history
and their honors history US history for
11th grade I'm an Adent professor at
Barry University I teach an anthropology
course there I guess I'm a general
intellectual I mean I I've changed my
research Focus around Ian um you know my
my doctoral research was on the Spanish
bass we talked about that in my last
book I'm creative I'm an artist I'm a
writer uh you know this next book coming
out is a book of
poetry um you know also probably going
to write a novel here soon and um and so
my my focus on anthropologically at
least I I had a full bright uh foreign
um senior scholarship to go to bra brail
and study Urban Indians and be a
visiting at the visiting professor at
the University do F Al
there and you um can you put on your
your best English accent for us maybe
introduce
your hasn't come out in a while yeah
yeah so introduce the introduce your new
book with an English
accent oh my introduce my book um with
an English accent well the the title of
my new book is uh the Forgotten
Shore so it's uh it's a um book of
poetry I've been writing poetry since I
was a little little kid wow and um I uh
and I've been also an artist since I was
a little kid so fortunately for me the
editor chose to include some of my
paintings uh with in the book and this
part the book so that was kind of nice
amazing um okay yeah so the book is uh
all right maybe maybe I'll try in
English action the Forgotten
sha that's forgotten sha yeah The Pick
of poetry by JP
lindro that's right I I can I can I can
do that without uh without feeling
guilty because my uh my mother happens
to be British yeah you have an ancestry
I don't I don't I kind of lost my
English a little bit because it's been a
while since I've been to the UK but yeah
and and John you it's you say you caught
you caught about 30 minutes of that
episode with uh with John kiraku what
did you think of that I really liked
that it was he's a really interesting
guy first of all and I I I agree with
you I think he's an American hero for uh
letting the American people know about
torture in relation to what the CIA was
doing post 911
of course uh the erosion of civil rights
from the Patriot
Act and also you know I've taught on
terrorism and and that subject as well
and so I find it very interesting you
know the bass had the terrorism thing
going for a while and I was working on
the bass peace process for a while
and so that that all that aspect is
quite interesting for me and and uh so I
I I I found it I found it very
interesting yeah for sure all right so
maybe we maybe at that tail end of this
we can get uh get some of your comments
but let's get into uh let's get into
some poetry here um sure and uh I think
you uh you know I was going to go after
this one uh first off are you prepared
to read uh read some of this to us or um
absolutely if you like me to I'll be
glad I mean I'll be glad to if you have
any ones that uh you particularly like
uh or I can choose one or two or
whatever whatever you think it's up to
you you're the I'm the host here yeah
okay so
um let me see so obviously the one the
one I I I want to go into is um and it's
only because I spent two years um and
you know I don't know if you knew this
or not but I I actually happened to meet
uh
um Vincente Fox who's a former president
of the Mexican Republic um wow I met him
while I was uh I was I was down in uh in
the yukatan uh for a couple a couple
years I was down there wow that's great
and um anyway so so I think as as as you
would know and is anybody who who else
has is kind of lived um I growing up in
growing up in California John we didn't
have the the the the the the best of
impressions of of of of Mexican I'm just
my perspective just what it was like for
me growing up and and when I was when I
was when I was asked to to live in
Mexico my eyes just kind of whoa wait a
second these are amazing people and
they're not all that the Mystique no or
media you know your Clint Eastwood
movies and whatever um right these are
loving beautiful amazing people and
absolutely you just you learn to love
their food you learn to love their dress
you learn to love their language
wonderful It's a Wonderful country and
they have so many different indigenous
populations and you have an affinity as
I do for the Mayan population there and
um they have a wonderful history and
archaeological history in prehistory and
pre-colonial history and it's it is just
a a wonderful country that's where I
first learned Spanish again in
kavaka oh wow I spent a summer in kavaka
and um and so I've I've had a love for
Mexico since very early on as
well I went through um and we'll get to
this P here but but I went through um
from from in route from dayf to aapco
there's something called The Devil's
elbow I think they call it or the
devil's turn or something it's like you
go you go up out of uh Mexico City and
then you go down uh into Guan vaka and
then you have you're you're doing like
60 and then you have to kind of slow
down to like 10 um to make this turn but
um um yeah so anyway so so we'll go
we'll go over to the the the peninsula
here and um and and and and let's let's
talk about mind memories um should I
read it or or do you have should I
okay if you'd like yeah I'll be glad if
I'd be very honored if you read it if
you'd like expain yeah okay so for
listeners Mayan memories this is uh JP
lindrith May
memories they buried us with our eyes
wide
open we were Isel Mayans we were
kjab all Mayans we were chush Mayans we
were Mayans we were AI Mayans we were
mom Mayans we were Ki Mayans we were K
Mayans we were
200,000 we
disappeared they buried us with our eyes
wide
open they were all lying on the ground
with their hands hands tied behind their
backs some were dead some were barely
moving and Alive the soldiers were
hitting them with machetes and blood was
everywhere they gathered all the women
and
children into one thatched HUD and burnt
It To The Ground the
screams were horrific and were
deafening they buried us with our eyes
wide open the gorillas came one night to
the house of my uncle asking for food we
called these people The Men Who came at
night they were trying to persuade
people to join them They Carried Away
three men I knew my uncle was
one when they did not come
back their families and mine went
looking
we found them in the corn fields some
had arms chopped
off their heads were barely attached to
their necks then the soldiers came at 4
a.m. they started shooting at all of us
terrified screaming everywhere running
woman and
children the next day we buried so many
of them in the fields we did not perform
any
ceremonies we were too
afraid they buried us with our eyes wide
open I was in the field on the hillside
picking maze beans and peppers they came
from behind me and took me three of them
soldiers all of them laughing laughing
laughing at me they put a scarf in my
mouth to muffle my screams they're
ripped away my red we peel and Corte and
tore off my underwear they were heavy on
top of me so heavy and they had bad
breath one had a mustache and
sideburns all of them kept laughing
taking
turns holding my arms holding my legs I
was shaking all over and could not stop
trembling and they buried us with eyes
wide
open my cousin disappeared one day one
day he just did not show
up and we never heard from him again by
then the Army had burnt down our house
and we were forced to stay with my
grandmother then one day the Army
brought my uncle in a coffin to our
house his head was still
bleeding my grandmother picked up his
arms and she could still move them they
were
flexible this is when we knew
he was killed not so long ago that is
when we decided to leave the mountains
and we left for elte for
good they buried
us with our eyes wide open our soul will
never
rest they buried
us with our
eyes wide
open well I have to ref frin from
drawing tear here and perhaps I should
have let it
out but it it makes me think of
something that I
know
the Mayan from my
understanding they had a calendar that
was more precise than that of the
Aztec and they were in tune with science
math astrology and in fact my
understanding is that what we know as
the number if it can be Quantified as
zero it was something that they
understood and they knew but what
invented zero that's correct yeah sure
yep but what I'm getting at John
is is my knowledge of Chichen and
the only knowledge is this and and this
is very interesting right that um I
don't know what was said in that 30
minutes that you caught but one thing
that John spoke of was the approach the
FBI had versus what the CIA had and the
CIA would torture these people and they
would be unresponsive yet the FBI says
hey let me offer you a a a food a date
let me give you something build a
rapport right
the the the the people people that
inadvertently had laid claim over the
land that the Mayan were living
upon
uh my understanding John it wasn't
until 1913 or maybe just before that
turn of the century there but somewhere
around there where it was a Harvard
Peabody U scientist um I think his name
was John th
um that that took a a British um painter
or or or Adventurer and they marched
into chichin and they began a
restoration effort and up and up until
that time um from the decline of
whenever the Mayan had stopped using
that particular city um chuchin was
nothing more than um trees growing out
out of it and bushes over growing on top
of
it so it's obviously it's how we
approach I mean this
poem makes me want to cry
John um thank you very much that's very
um I'm very honored by you saying that
joh that Ian and um you know the the
you're right the first epigraphers were
the turn of the 20th century
um and I was just thinking that you
know just going you know relating to
what John
kirow um said you know glal changed
after the CIA coup there in 1950 right
with our Ban's
government and because we had Plantation
interest
there you the AR Ben's government was
seen as too
liberal so that government was
overthrown
and um we trained a lot of these
military people in the school of the
Americas they committed these atrocities
that led
to the genocide in Guatemala
so the quote um they buried us with
their eyes with our eyes wide open comes
from a Harvard scholar Anthropologist
and medical doctor named Paul Farmer who
worked who has worked and still works
quite a bit in the developing world and
that was a quote from him
that he um you know from some of his
informants that he interviewed about
post um Guatemala post uh genocide post
Civil
War and also the other the
other stories within that poem come
directly from inter interviews I had
with people of of memories of that
genocide and legal depositions that
lawyers in Florida
took uh from memories of that genocide
so that rape story is from a legal
deposition the story of the uncle uh
being brought to the house after he was
newly killed or assassinated um that was
from a interview that I conducted with
an informant who who shared
her memories of her family um and her as
a
child um from that atrocity and and so
so these are this poem is actually based
on real stories and real
people's memories and and how they felt
and to be buried with your eyes wide
open um in in the Mayan culture is like
a crime because you know they have all
these kind of indigenous ceremonies and
ceremonies with incense and it combines
you know C Catholicism and
synchronicity but you know the soul in
other words their souls have not rested
because of that their need their eyes
needed to be closed they need to be
reburied and they what they meant by
that was that they didn't go through the
ceremony to have closure for the for
their souls to have
rest and so that's what that phrase
means means that they were they us with
with our eyes wide
open wow wow I mean wow that's just
that's deep and you're telling me that
you've been writing poetry as a child
since you were a child since I was a
little kid like I and it's probably also
my interest in Native Americans and I
had an interest in animals and natural
being a naturalist as well and so I've
been yeah I've been lighting since I was
a little kid and and this is my uh first
attempt at more of a complete book
and uh you know it's about a Pages now
so it'll come out the first week of
January I'm sorry that I I couldn't give
you a copy earlier we we had a bit of a
publishing
delay but that's what happen
so uh very anyway very thoughtful of you
um so wow and and you know I I I these
these ancient civilizations the um you
know the year the the the Europeans um
as an overall from a governmental
standpoint I mean we at the the the the
natives that were living on this land
before uh before Europeans arrived you
know they're all forced to integrate or
put on reservations and right so yeah so
the so the Mayan civilization had
collapsed before the Spanish arrived
right okay and the classic Maya culture
because chichito you just mentioned is a
postclassic site and I'm sorry that I
know a little bit about this just
because that yeah I was I studied
archaeology you know and I actually went
down to uh bise with Florida State and I
was part of their archaeological program
we were
Excavating sort of incipient maze
agriculture to see if maze began in that
region uhuh and we also were looking at
um you know different sites and I found
a a a burial like the LA one of the last
days that we were there you know the the
mai used to bury their dead under their
houses and we found like a 3000 year
burial or whatever
was so so chichin is actually a post
classic site and it's influenced by toex
and from more Central Mexico because by
that time the classic Maya period had
collapsed and probably mostly do but
among many things what mostly do sorry
my
mostly due to to Warfare um but there's
a whole other factors that why that
culture civilization collapsed right so
many
factors uhuh so they but you you know
what what is interesting is that
elements uh survive and and and
certainly architecturally elements
survive but um so like for instance when
I when I met this um Vincente Fox um
which was in a small little village of
viad deled
uh in that little village which is just
outside of it's kind of the area tourist
stop for food and gas before uh before
getting to uh to Chichen which is about
30 40 minutes to its West um in in right
in front of that Convent the convent the
convento San Bernardino um was where I
met him and um in this little village um
English is very scarce uh Spanish is
also very scarce most of these people in
in this Village and certainly the the
smaller Villages outside of it um that's
what they speak is
Mayan and um and so we we I learned a
few phrases I mean BOS kaik is is one of
them and I think that may have been that
basically means K Pasa
but when I was reading your poem it kind
of started the pronunciation kind of
started coming coming back to me a bit
right right um those very difficult
indigenous words right yeah Fox I really
like that guy he's a he's a really
interesting intellectual me Mexican
intellectual and uh he's been a very
outspoken CR critic of this current
government of ours yeah um but he's he
has a good sense of humor too but he
must have been really interesting to
talk to and meet Ian I EnV you for that
yeah yeah H thank you uh and of course
my Mex my favorite Mexican-American
writer is Carlos fenes Carlos Fuentes I
I I I I don't know him well but I
certainly recognize the
name yeah he he wrote a book called The
Death of artmo Cruz which is the about
the Mexican Revolution Civil War which I
really like wow again another book
another novel novel about memory
I yeah panilla Milan
saato um yeah yeah that's right that's
right so let's uh let's get into uh
let's get into in kafka's mind can we
can we go
there so oh I'm sorry in kafka's mind
sure we can do that should I read
it sure I mean you're the you're the
host why not I'm very honored for you to
read my
poems okay so in kafka's Mind by JP
lindra and again let me just mention JP
for for those
interested uh in in your Publications is
it what's your what's your your main web
destination so academia.edu
and that you'll find all my Publications
pretty
much uh academia.edu is a academic
website um connecting academics all over
the world really and there's like 50
million academics connected on that
website and I just I it's just um a
place where it's kind of like a you know
it's a Social Media Forum you put your
your Publications there and people look
them up and you know if you put them
there then more people will look at them
and so on and and actually you're you
know I'd put your link to the radio show
that when we talked last time I put it
there and there's quite a few people uh
accessing that and looked at that and
downloaded that so so before we read
this and uh I feel honored that you uh
want me to read it and certainly will
before we read this
um describe to
listeners who is Kafka and what what is
the uh what is this poem
about okay so France
kofka France
cka um is an existential is an
existential Jewish
writer um lived at the turn of the
century he unfortunately died as a young
man um but basically with some
complications of like tuberculos
tuberculosis I think he starved uh
because he was so ill he couldn't get
food
down but basically he had all these
writings and
manuscripts and he had this friend named
Max bro
and Kafka you know on his death bed he
was so ill he's he he had mentioned to
his friend you know just burn all my my
manuscripts just you know
get rid of
them and thankfully uh Max brood didn't
follow his friends directive and end up
publishing publishing them and so we
have a
wonderful we have a a lot of these kind
of um how do I want to say the um
distopic visions of the world and very
existentialist visions of the world
um you have the the book The Trial you
know you're it's this person who's on
trial and he doesn't know what he's
crimes he's charged of and this kind of
gets into your last interview with John
Kira like it's just kind of
this the state the state Authority
having to able to do whatever it wants
at the expense of the
individual and that's a theme that runs
throughout um his writings and and being
kopka being Jewish uh having been
persecuted in that that era from you
know racism and and prejudice against
Jewish people are pretty
prevalent and you know he also wrote uh
the short novel The Noel the
metamorphosis
where a man basically becomes an insect
um he wrote a short story called The
Hunger Artist where the hunger the
artist is on display in a cage kind of
like black panther as he describes it
and you know how this artists are you
know basically starving for their art
and so on and so forth so for many
people and many writers
Kafka represents this kind of a darker
aspect of humanity but and and he's very
much like George Orwell and his dystopic
vision of the world but at the same time
he's also kind of a precursor to people
like uh kamu and French writer
Kimu and uh and other writers like U sh
Paul SAR and people like that but it's
unfortunate he died so young but we were
you know as a as Humanity we were very
fortunate that his
poems his poem sorry his novels and his
writings and His short stories were
actually published and so I identify
with Kasa in this kind of his vision of
the world in the way
so let's get to describe I don't know if
I did a good job or not but yeah but
that's how I would two before we get
into it two things that popped into my
mind while you were describing that
is one are you familiar with the Poo vo
if I pronounced that right pop Vu Vu the
PO Vu yes yes of
course um so so so that's something that
popped into my mind and and and and the
the other thing that popped in my mind
it just escaped me um but um but anyway
for for for for listeners who aren't
aware of what the pple Vu was when when
you'd mentioned when You' mentioned uh
burning of uh I it just came back in my
mind when you'd mentioned burning of of
uh transcripts and and and documents and
and and and work that was that was
written this is
what the PPU
vo is and was but it's elements of the
history of the uh of the Mayan a tribe
of the May a Kesh I think it is just
looking at the Wikipedia here for it um
and it was so so when when these the PO
is a sacred Central text of the Mind
culture in the sense of their vision of
the afterlife right okay and there was
these twin twin hero Gods twin hero gods
that are
uh sacrifice and then sacrifice
themselves and then the the the gods of
death in the Underworld try to kill them
and then they regenerate and so they
overcome death in other words got it
okay I didn't know that so the constant
theme in in the Mayan culture with the
Poo Vu is regeneration of
life and death is prevalent because you
know the May has practice human
sacrifice and so on and so forth so the
the twin heroes from the PO Vu are part
of that mythology is you know their
reasons why they they had Human
Sacrifice so the pop Vu is their their
Notions of the underworld and that's why
caves are
so sacred to the Mayan people because
they are entrances to that Under World
which is represented the pople yeah
interesting yeah um the other thing that
had come to my mind as you were
describing kofka was um so since we've
spoken last I've I've brought in um and
this is maybe what you caught if you
were listening to the beginning of this
uh segment uh Julie Gomez um is um is a
she's she's joined
um a staff that that that I'm creating
now and and she's a local journalism
student but uh she'll be contributing on
a weekly basis uh various various items
of of of research and and um today she
spoke about net neutrality but last week
she spoke about um um Guantanamo Bay and
and and this is this is why there's
relevance here because these prisoners
at Guantanamo are drawing um these what
seem to be the images that I've seen I
don't know how they've gotten out but
beautiful kind of um sunset sunrise you
know right yeah their art yeah I've seen
that yes yes yes I saw that and the uh
unfortunately the US military on The
Stance of that is to destroy uh destroy
this um from what I know and so she'
kind of looked in that a little bit but
um but anyway so uh that's a that's a
segue but uh you know we can kind of um
we can put together
um ends ends that make a make a spark um
uh the human bind is is
is is is it's interesting that guat
there's a whole I think there's a
curator I can't remember where I but um
there's a curator and there's an exhibit
of their drawings and their paintings
I think it's I if I'm not mistaken it's
the Metropolitan Museum of Art or the or
it's the Museum of Modern Art m one of
the two and they're displaying their
artwork oh they are okay they're
displaying it from what I've read from
what I saw on television or whatever I I
just saw it
briefly okay so um in cfas in K kafka's
mind in kafka's
mind it reads us reads reads us this
again uh by JP
linstruth in the darkest
recesses the indignant regresses and the
constant obsessive obsessive
self-loathing
feelings thoughts growing reings
inquisitions in disqui itude
dis attritions in plentitude
bureaucrats in Shadow
plays all autocrats shallow
displays an
insurance technocrat and yet a writer
true how even then he knew bring for the
glowing Moon alluding to the gloaming
and unending Doom denials in
obfuscation trials without
causation God or
no flawed
fellow Judaism cloaked from others
racism times of incipient
fascism
oceanless atheism and socialist
activism sometimes his animal magnetism
and stoic
skepticism self
aggrandizing substitutes women for
fathers ebony
caligraphy
womanizing prostitutes
pornography galvanizing
fortitude permutes with those haunting
others varying
enigmatic
iconography so many
near betro s or mere woman in
broils the oipal dis approving
patriarch the
contemptible ucing
birthmark burn the notebooks with
bonfire burn them all spurn with an
auster Outlook mired in Ernest Thal the
prodigious godsend Max broad
accusations and
precations of nonsensical
crimes
unethical persecutions of
nightmarish
times epical tragedies without Absol
perishing in his prime who are the
accusers and abusers conjurers and users
of dark arts witness black Pagan hearts
daggered with poisoned arrows
tuberculosis sickness flagrant fictive
counterparts lagered treasons without
reason dead sparrows torturous
confusions with life's many
delusions profusions of doubts and
pinoid
whereabouts the insane and the profane
concealed Mysteries of the inan lunatic
conspiracies with wax and Wayne heretic
histories of great pain obsessions with
unknown entities confessions of
non-rgd felonies without apparent
remedies shadowed loneliness hollowed
obliqueness nonetheless hollowed out to
confess Transformations into slimy
Vermin into bug into insect damnations
through pensively burning through
hallucinations without
drugs mental
malformations hitherto the
Eternal suspect cir irum spect
frustrations hideous
Sensations and piteous
minations felt muscled black leopard in
hunger knelt muffled shuffled attacked
poetic Shepherd recompense for the
offense of starvation and defense of
deprivation personal
privations ravenous pacing in the cage
callous debasing on the stage muted
oligarchy of the forboding Fortress
disputed citizenry of encoding
thoughtless reputed hierarchy of goding
conscious to the void to the abyss to
nothingness to avoid to miss to the
senseless devoid remiss
Timeless paranoid
reminisce Oblivion Darkness destroyed
resist Unforgiven civilian
hopeless absurd isolation abject
frustration incurred desolation
disconnected
narration oppression and regression
living in Eternal fear non-
intercessions from
transgressions on forgiving infernal and
aere convert depression horrendous and
ever tragic overt
suppression portentious and endeed Manic
and
pathologic an allergy to the
forom and forsaken
Outcast the apoy of him born to
accusations
unsurpassed
yes thank
you in kafka's
mind that's a lot going on um yes and I
and you have to understand like in that
home I I tried to Encompass all his
writings all his thoughts all
his
um all what he represented in his
writings and also his personal biography
as
well wow um there there's some words in
there obviously that I uh didn't know
how to pronounce nor did I know the
meaning of but um right one of my my
editors one of the thing he said is that
John you know your your your your your
poetry can be intellectually challenging
and it and it and it um challenges the
reader right it's yeah challenging to
the
reader right
so but it's meant to be that way in a
way and I guess I was very much
influenced by the the Irish poet
laureate um Sheamus Haney in that in
that
regard and how how
so Sheamus Haney um writes in very
symbolic and obscure ways and he has a
way of turning a phrase
or having meaning that and the first
representation is not you know it's not
what it's being represented you know a
bog can be the conflict in Northern
Ireland for example
and so there's a lot of hidden meeting
and and and as I mentioned in my preface
of This Book Is
that what I try to represent is an
archaeology of emotions and you know I'm
getting that notion that idea from Melle
Fuko is a French
philosopher his notion of the idea of
archaeology of knowledge
where in in in my view of how interpret
that is that the reader has to dig to
understand kind of the emotions that are
being brought forward in this in this in
the
writing so forgotten
Shore includes it looks like you've got
80 poems in there is that
right um I think there're how many do I
have I think
it's 36 poems that's 80 pages ah 80
pages okay yeah and what 3 38 poems May
yeah sorry um what um what what is what
what poem um sticks out in your mind is
um being one that I uh kind of portrays
the Forgotten Shore whatever that you
know thank you um I guess it depends on
who the reader is in the audience and
what they want to get out of it I
mean you know part of it was writing
about my divorce and uh and going
through those emotions and so the
Forgotten Shore itself I mean there's a
poem um the last poem of the of the book
is the Forgotten Shore which the which
the um the book is named after and the
idea of the Forgotten Shore is that it's
a place that you know somehow that the
love you had for this other person broke
off and you're kind of left on this
forgotten Shore could be like an island
or it could be a beach somewhere be
somewhere where you feel
forgotten but what I I wrote in the
prepet too is that what's not evident to
the reader necessarily is that um you
know that the there's hope you know
there's hope to find love again there's
hope to find love once more that you
don't miss neily need to stay on that
forgotten
Shore um so that's one of the things and
then there's more humorous poems
actually in the book too I
mean uh you know I have one uh which is
an O to dogs um I have one about a a
little uh
ant philosophies about and then there's
a lot of Greek mythology in there
there's a lot about art there an artist
and then there's some natural
observations as well I mean I have one
about the lockah river and then I have
others about other
rivers so there's a there's a little bit
of everything in there um certainly it's
about love and loss and memories of loss
and it's also about um biographies of
people too people that I've I've known
like my grandparents and things like
that so there's a little bit of
everything I think in
it John how how long is the this
compilation take for you to put
together you know some of the poems are
years
old um some were WR written recently you
know a few like about four of the poems
this past
year um I put together in kind of a a
frenzy
of artistic inspiration um majority of
poems within a within the eighth month
even a six to 8th month period I had
some a lot of the poems that are the
majority of the book but like O2 a child
for example that's that's an old old
that's a that's a poem to uh my brother
whose wife had a miscarriage the third
term of their pregnancy was kind of
sad and then the veil is about my
experiences in Sevilla Spain and kind of
take on that the Adon Sak is about
Basque fishermen which I kind of studied
in The Basque country in
Spain and then there's you know other
things you know things that poems that
were written I guess in memory of my
ex-wife and there's poems even a couple
poems about Casi in there who I wished
happy birthday
tonight and then so there's a little bit
of everything so that's um
yeah and what what type of uh reception
is the book getting and maybe it's
probably too new to Market if it hasn't
even come out yet
so it's it's supposed to have been
published in in December but we had a
hiccup because the poem that you just
read and again I'm very honored that
You' read it in kafka's mind um for
whatever reason in the back and forth
between edits and looking at drafts U my
editor just forgot to include it and so
I asked him can he include it and he
did so it's just that's been a delay so
hopefully um I'll have the books um uh
coming out the first week of January and
they'll be going out to all those who
had supported um my uh Indiegogo
campaign to to actually pre-bi the books
uh for to help with the
production so um you know there was but
um L fortunately too is that the um the
editor the well the publishing the
publisher of the book poet um poetic
Matrix press um had its 20th anniversary
this past year
2017 and so they they put me in the
antology I was very fortunate about that
and I I really like the editor he's his
name is John Peterson he's in
California in Northern California and uh
you know and and so I just feel very
fortunate Ian that it actually got
published because I I wasn't even sure
if
somebody would pick them up um you know
art is very subjective and as Z know and
uh and so somebody may not like some
writings of somebody and somebody else
might not like it and sure you know you
always hear about these novelist you
know of the past that might not be
published today because of how they
wrote write or wrote whatever
so poetic Matrix press yeah yes but how
do how do you think I mean would what
are your thoughts in just having read a
couple of them homes I'm just curious
what well I mean this is you know this
is this is this is Art and and and I
didn't error my show last week because
um art bosel came into town and so this
this little station that I um that I
that I broadcast from uh here on 27th
and I think it's third um they uh they
kind of got overrun with with art
programming so um
oh okay my slot uh got uh got uh got got
got used used up by by the art so I
didn't I didn't go last week but um this
you know it's it's it's it's it's this
is this to to me this is Art this is
just a form of art right I mean um thank
you yes thank it's um it's it's it's
it's really it's a it's a and this is
this is another thing that I'm equating
it to so um next uh I'm going to start
the new year off uh with uh with a guest
named Dan Winter he's a fractal field
field theorist and and scientist um W
former systems analyst at IBM but he's
currently uh Consulting for virtual
reality computers um I mean you know the
way that this guy thinks is and he uses
a lot of golden ratio if you're familiar
with um with with what what that is and
and in in in in kind of his his theor
theor of um I guess how man is able to D
used the golden ratio quite often that's
correct yeah okay yeah it sounds
familiar um so he's gonna kick off 2018
for for for for my show and um right um
you know it's it's it's basically he
also talks a lot about um um a couple a
couple of well a few people um one would
be John D the other one would would be
Sir Francis Bacon and the other one
would be Shakespeare and um and
certainly um the the initial two
actually
influenced um the writings of
Shakespeare and we know certainly that
Shakespeare is influenced by um some
incredible ancient Linguistics of of of
the past so um that's that's the first
thing that kind of comes to my mind um
John is is is how crafty uh you've been
able to formulate um your words and um
you know that first one just really
spoke to me
um and I think maybe that's because you
know because I I know a little bit about
um part of that culture but uh yeah
just the the words that that you used
with the with the woman who had
been abused uh it's um I a previous
guest I've had on the program is um um
she incepted uh the uh the me too um
Toronto B right me too hashtag and and
and so um I I just it's
anyway the the ways that you're able to
speak um without
speaking right yeah is
phenomenal no thank you I I that's I'm
very humbled by saying that yeah it's a
form of communication I'm trying to
communicate feelings to the world
and doing it in a very symbolic way
and you know it's a whole different type
of writing John than an academic book or
a popular book or yeah or whatever or
what have you I mean
it's you know it is the use of a lot of
symbolism and a lot of iconography and
things that come to mind and to
represent and I I I personally I like I
like Greek mythology I go back to it and
I guess
because you know one of the things that
I when I was a little kid I I I was at
grade school I was taught the Greek
Mythology by this great English teacher
that I had and and I just really fell in
love with it and I since then I've you
know I've kind of infused my poems with
it but in a lot of ways you know in this
if you look at the history of I guess
English literature the or Western
thought of you I think you had mentioned
even earlier on that Greek Greek thought
has
influenced how we all think right and
the mythology or
classic ways of paradigms of teaching
lessons about the world too so so that I
think that that's quite
important wellow yeah yeah it's funny
you mentioned um Greek mythology I I
spent a few years in school in in in
Oregon and uh there's a there's a very
large well-known um apparel company for
athletics that emerged from the
institution um and so I too actually I I
I remember taking these art history
classes from uh from uh a guy that uh I
think it was um I don't know if he had
gone to Brown or I'm not sure where he
but he but he had studied he' studied a
sculpture in ancient sculpture um called
the critius boy and um and it was um it
was Jeff's kind of uh understanding of
the way that the sculpture was uh
designed that he's looking at it and I
don't know if it was in the British
museum or where it was he looking at and
he says he says wait a second that head
and you know this kind of sent shock
waves around the kind of world of the
crus boy and and those who were studying
it and interesting this head is not
properly displayed and it needs to be
adjusted you know this way and
so that was kind of that was nobody had
caught on to that previous and and and I
don't really know what led to him
understanding that and realizing that
that needed to be made but um I used to
love those uh those classes that he
would talk about uh um Athena and and
and the Acropolis and yeah so you and I
do we I think I can um understand your
fascination with h with that culture as
well no thank you yeah for for sure and
uh yeah I mean I um you know when you
sometimes when you ask an artist like
you know how did you come up with that
idea or what inspired you for this or
that or whatever yeah know sometimes
it's hard you're hard put to like put it
all together but you know I can say
basic EV you know some of the basic
events in my life that led to writing
that or whatever and
uh you know and as I mentioned before
it's you know the the love lost or a
parent or a grandparent having died or
or or finding love again or or just
observing nature and all its power and
Beauty to me are in different
Inspirations right there's different
levels of inspiration or even just even
an artist like kofka a writer like kofka
who really never saw the fruition of his
Works being published he really didn't
want them to be
published um ended up has end up being
one of the greatest writers in
the in the world world
literature yeah but just you know that's
a thing I mean
about about art and you can say the same
thing for kind of an artist like Vana
know van or
Picassa you
know I once asked uh Oliver Stone this
was in San Francisco at a movie theater
where he was giving a discussion of
uh uh one of his uh I don't remember the
name of that film but um sakario no that
that was somebody different um anyway
one of his films and um and you know
he'd done these previous he'd done
platoon he'd done Wall Street and
whatever and I
says he's taking a Q&A Q&A and I stand
up and I said I said I said Oliver what
drives you you what what what drives you
and you know as you're talking you know
about kind of what went into you
creating this piece if you will if you
can kind of singular sing singularize it
um I'm thinking you know hey what drives
what drove Hemingway right to uh to to
to do what he was doing and and and and
and the basic response that I got from
uh from from Oliver and I'd have to go
back and Replay that but um because a
friend of mine actually recorded it but
the basic response that I remember
getting from from Oliver was um
basically the same message
of I want to deliver truth to the world
you know I want to deliver uh right
something of of of of of of honesty and
I there like this this underlying
there's this underlying kind of
foundation for all of us that kind of
you know hey look here here's this woman
in in in in in Guatemala that you know
is she's like hey I was I was raped I
need help this is wrong and there's
there's like this there's who's her
voice right who's that woman's voice
right how do how do you capture a victim
like that um you know there's a whole
debate on Art and Trauma and art and
horror like you know like after the
Holocaust for example Ian like are you
really supposed to write about
such an un unspeakable horror such as
the Holocaust right after it happened
and and that was a h that's been that
was a huge debate and then of course you
had people like PR Prima leevy who wrote
about it and then you had Vil who wrote
you know the night
um and uh and of course people did end
up writing about it and did I guess
create art from from tragedy from
trauma um but but but like for example
you know how how can you accompass that
woman's horror that her trauma I mean
it's
uh you know un the Unspeakable aspects
of humanity I mean it's yeah these are
you know and then an art supposed to to
being the most elevated right so it's
that
contrast
yeah JP uh share with us um as we'll uh
we'll wrap things up here um share with
us share with us your your your next
project where where you're where you're
taking your uh your career
next thanks for asking so um I have a a
book in the works that um it's called
the civilizing abuses
um uh ammer
um emmer
indigenes um
and um in in in the in an Amazonian City
and basically it's about my research in
in Brazil on on Urban and Indian groups
but I'm also um you know I'll be
starting more of a creative project I've
already really started uh writing a
novel um I wrote I wrote a novel you
when I was I finished novel when I was
23 a 500 page book that I had an agent
in New York and everything and uh I
didn't want to change the ending so it
ended up being shelv at the Broan
Library which is a a library for
non-published writers but but I'm I'm
still interested in that genre and I I I
you know so future writing wise I have a
non-fiction book and I have a fiction
book at work
now incredible incredible John um wow
thank you you impress me more and more
all the
[Laughter]
time I'm very humbled and I assure you
I'm I'm you know I don't want to come
off some intellectual snob or anything
like that yeah well you
don't you don't um wow okay so um
awesome
um that'll wrap things up for us and um
I just make a comment on hemway though
yes of course because you know I I've
read everything that the guy's written
okay and then I encountered somebody
that who had also done that and to me as
a Young Man Hemingway was the
fundamental
writer um I mean he's been my
inspiration to to write maybe it's the
clarity of his Pros but also the kind of
life he
led and the sad thing of course is that
he committ suicide at the end
but uh he was interesting guy um and and
the reason why I comment on on Hemingway
in particular is
that he's a you know a very quential
American writer not only being part of
what Gert Stein called The Lost
Generation Um defining you know the the
writers after World War
I but he defined a whole new kind
of way of writing
pros and uh you know I think a lot of a
lot of few a lot of his works are
Classics that should be are in the Canon
of of American literature should also be
read again and again
so anything in particular that stands
out with you from him and how he
impressed you Hemingway
yeah
um uh well let's see he he his short
story writing I mean there's a short
story called Hills like white
elephants which is about um a little
short story about whether or
not the woman he's with should have an
abortion or not it's quite a quite a
telling piece and it's quite a and it's
all obscure and you don't really know it
um you don't really kind of you have to
figure it out kind of by the
end but you know of course uh the the
novel that probably got him the garnered
him the Nobel Prize was old man the
sea you know this the the Journey of
this old man with this giant marlin that
he catches and keeps it tied up to the
to the boat and all the sharks attack
the fish
and he's really not left with much by
the time he returns to shore but having
you know had caught the great fish and
so on MH and I and so and you know what
attracts me or what what draws me to
Hemingway himself I
mean you know there's so much uh maybe
those Paris years I
know uh um a Movable Feast is great
collection of
stories of course he and Fitzgerald
Scott s knew each other and didn't
really like each other or used to make
fun of that Scott
but
um I don't know I mean I you know maybe
it's just kind of maybe being a
sportsman and and all those kind of
things
that were kind of interesting when I was
growing up as a
teenager not that I condone you know big
game hunting or anything like that
nowadays
but um I just just the way that he
writes and is able to carry a mood in
very short senses I think is one of his
gifts
um and and proves that American
literature is belongs in all the great
literatures of the
world and he's one of the writers that
did
that well said very well
said uh JP thank you for uh thank you
for coming on the show safe travels
thank you thank you and um happy
birthday again right happy birthday to
uh your girlfriend to Tasia I really
appreciate that and I thank you so much
for the invitation I I know that um you
know you know the the the genre poach is
that something that us you probably
cover in your programs but I I
appreciate you in inviting me on again
on your show for an interesting
discussion and for agreeing to have
read um a couple of my poems I'm very
honored that you did so and uh you know
and and I'm and of course I'd like to uh
keep you in mind as as writing projects
come up and as I get have more
Publications that we could talk again
hopefully yes I I'm looking forward to
it
absolutely me too and I will definitely
be sending you a copy of the book as
soon as I have it in my
hands very kind of you very very kind
very kind yeah
yeah okay so um anyway uh if you could
if you could one last time uh throw out
that website that people can uh can go
to that would be awesome Yes um it's
academia.edu
and it
um you know you can go there for free
you can also sign up for free um and if
it's a good resource even for students
or for really anybody who's interested
in kind of Academia academic writing if
you want to download an article you just
type in a subject you might be
interested in you know or just type A
you know like anthropology and a lot of
a lot of Articles will pop up or
Amazonian Indians and a lot of a lot of
Articles will pop up so it's it's just a
good resource for information as well um
you know for academics as a way of
connecting with other academics but it's
also just a good resource
for you know idea books to read read or
articles to read and so
on very cool very cool ladies and
gentlemen and the publisher of this is
poetic Matrix press gotten Shore and
they're where are they based in uh so
they're in California yeah Berkeley or
sanco it will be available on amazon.com
by the way okay okay ptic Matrix ladies
and gentlemen JP
lindroth JP until next
time yes thank thank you so much all
right bye take care
bye JP
linth has
a doctorate of
philosophy and is an incredibly gifted
writer
um he
rejoins discussions rejoins this program
for for uh a second time and uh the
first time he was on
um he was it just happened that
Pascal um and he were talking about the
same thing and in a sense and so um I
was able to pair the discussion together
um I got another sneeze woman
okay pardon me and um and it was a
discussion regarding um Spain and the
Bosque region so this was this was the
first time I got to spend um time
one-on-one with JP and um what a
wonderful uh show we we were able to
deliver uh to this uh this
afternoon I will be back in two
weeks the 3rd of January I'll be back to
in the New
Year I'll be back with fractal field
seist and scientist Dan
Winter and as I mentioned
earlier I've got a
lineup of a few different folks that'll
be joining in January but but two of
them
uh we we'll concentrate on vaccine
education Barbara low Fisher co-founder
and president of the national vaccine
information center her books articles
and research have appeared in the New
York Times Wall Street Journal
Washington Post USA Today Time Magazine
and
Newsweek she's also appeared on CNN CBS
FOX MSNBC alzer NPR and NBC's Today Show
and like past guest Rachel Ross she's
actually also been on the
doctors CBS is the doctors Rachel was a
main stay Barbara has appeared on it but
Barbara will be bringing her knowledge
and research of vaccines and her um
movement to
educate in regard to the program next
month and we'll also be joined by Dr
Sher J ten Penney osteopathic medical
doctor
uh so we've got some great things
happening here and uh it'll be an
exciting exciting exciting New Year if
you're still listening happy birthday
again
to JP's girlfriend down in Brazil be
safe and uh uh enjoy uh enjoy JP
um and I leave you today with the same
words that I always leave
with I'm going to add happy holidays and
happy New Year and until next time
ladies and gentlemen I am your host Ian
Hamilton trer you've tuned in to
discussions on Winwood
radio.com follow me on Twitter i a n t r
TT i r follow me on Instagram Facebook
if you choose and the words
are
be
awesome